deloitteresources.com 2006-10-22

# Global Home Page - Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu

**DELOITTE RESOURCES PRIVACY STATEMENT**

**Introduction**

Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu (“DTT”) is a privacy conscious global organization.  The following statement sets forth DTT’s privacy policy for its global intranet platform, Deloitte Resources, and the sites and applications hosted by this intranet platform (together “Deloitte Resources”). The privacy statement describes how Deloitte Resources collects and processes personal data.

Please note that Deloitte Resources also contains links to sites maintained and controlled by DTT, its member firms and third party organizations that are not part of the Deloitte Resources platform. These sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You are responsible for familiarizing yourself with the privacy policies of any non-participating site you visit by clicking on a link provided by Deloitte Resources.

**Information Collection**

Deloitte Resources limits the information collected from partners, directors, employees and other authorized users to only the minimum information necessary to fulfill its function as a global resource for the Deloitte community.

Users are authenticated when logging in to Deloitte Resources either by directly entering their Active Directory user name and password or through single sign on access.  Users may also complete  a  personal profile by providing business related personal data including, but not limited to, name, email address, business function, office location and telephone number to the Global People Directory (“People Directory”). When providing data to the People Directory, users are informed that they may choose whether or not to submit certain information, such as resumes and personal photos, and whether they want this information published in the People Directory.   The purpose of the People Directory is to provide accurate and updated contact and other business-related information on all Deloitte Resources users in order to facilitate communication and cooperation among DTT Member Firms and people and the distribution of business updates and other materials. Platform sites may also collect personal data such as your job title, professional skills and competencies, and resume data in order to fulfill their particular functions.

Where Deloitte Resources seeks non-mandatory information, you will be notified at the time the data is requested that such information is not required. If you, on your own, choose to submit personal data, you are consenting to DTT’s use of such data in accordance with this privacy statement.

Deloitte Resources does not usually seek any sensitive data (e.g., data relating to race or ethnic origin, religious beliefs, criminal record, physical or mental health, or sexual orientation) from users.  We will, where necessary, obtain your explicit consent to the collection and use of such information.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

Deloitte Resources utilizes “cookies” to identify users when they connect to the site. A user’s browser must be enabled to allow cookies in order to access the site. Upon successful login a cookie is created and placed on the user’s machine. The cookie expires when the user is logged off Deloitte Resources. In addition to information related to authentication, information may be stored in the cookie in order to direct a user to the correct site location.

In addition, to ensure that our global intranet platform is well managed and to facilitate improved navigation within the platform, we or our service provider(s) may use cookies or Web beacons (electronic images that allow Deloitte Resources to count users who have accessed a particular page or platform site, and to access certain cookies) to collect aggregate data. We may use such devices to track information on our systems and identify categories of users by items such as IP address, domain, browser type and URLs and pages visited. This information is reported to our Webmasters who use the information to analyze the number of users to different platform sites and areas to make sure that Deloitte Resources is serving as a useful, effective information source. Neither our cookies nor Web beacons collect any personal data such as your name or email address.

**Internal Email Privacy Statement**

Please [read our internal email privacy statement](https://www.deloitteresources.com/pgContent.aspx?cid=64398) to learn about the measures in place to protect your privacy when you receive emails sent by or on behalf of the DTT leadership or various DTT groups or functions.

**Information Use**

Deloitte Resources uses personal data for necessary and limited purposes only.  In general, personal data may be used to contact you with firm updates and other relevant information; to perform surveys of usefulness to Deloitte Resources; and to create and maintain firm directories. Platform sites may also use personal data to schedule client engagements and to facilitate communication within particular service lines or groups whose members may be located in different jurisdictions.

**Data Disclosure**

Some platform sites use strict access controls (e.g. passwords, etc.) to restrict disclosure of personal data collected by the sites. For other sites it may be necessary to make personal data accessible to all Deloitte Resources users in order to ensure that anyone with a legitimate business need is able to use the data (i.e. for contact purposes, to schedule and fill engagements, etc.).

Although Deloitte Resources may provide users’ personal data to service providers that handle information on its behalf, information will usually not be shared with third parties for secondary or unrelated purposes unless otherwise disclosed at the point of collection.

Personal data may be transmitted internationally through the Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu worldwide organization or to third parties when necessary to achieve the purpose for which such information was submitted. This may include transfer to countries without data protection rules similar to those in effect in a particular user’s country of residence. By providing information to DTT through its global intranet platform, you are explicitly consenting to such transfers.

Where appropriate, personal data may be disclosed to law enforcement, regulatory or other government agencies or third parties where necessary or desirable to comply with legal or regulatory obligations or requests.

**Access to Information**

Deloitte Resources is dedicated to providing you reasonable opportunity to access and review your personal data and correct any inaccuracies it may contain. You may choose to edit and update your personal profile in the Global People Directory at anytime. In all cases the Deloitte Resources sites will treat requests to access information or change information in accordance with applicable legal requirements.

**Information Security**

Deloitte Resources has in place reasonable commercial standards of technology and operational security to protect all information provided by and on users from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu reserves the right to modify or amend this privacy statement at any time and for any reason. Nothing contained herein is intended to create a contract or agreement between Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu and any user visiting Deloitte Resources or providing personal data of any kind.

**Users' Questions and Comments**

If you should have any questions regarding Deloitte Resources’ privacy statement or do not feel that your concerns have been addressed, please  [Contact Us](mailto:dttresponsecenter@deloitte.com?Subject=Deloitteresources.com%20Feedback)
